Judith Raskin Papers, 1911-2000
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
Judith Raskin papers
1911-2000
Raskin, Judith
MS 126
24 boxes (14 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Opera singer and teacher. Raskin made her professional debut on both the stage and television, specializing in Schubert, Mozart, Lieder and Yiddish songs. The bulk of the Raskin papers focus on her professional life, and include publicity, reviews, programs, and taped recordings of performances. Personal materials include correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks and diaries, primarily from her years as a student at Smith College. Notable correspondents include Beverly Sills, Eugene Ormandy, and William Maxwell.
Judith Raskin was born June 21, 1928, daughter of Harry Raskin and Lillian Mendelsohn Raskin. Both her parents were public school teachers and instilled in their only child a love of music, the subject Judith Raskin majored in when she came to Smith College in 1945. She graduated from Smith in 1949 and received an honorary degree in 1963. While at Smith, Raskin studied with Anna Hamlin, continuing her lessons with Hamlin even after graduation as she began pursuing her career in opera. In 1948, Raskin married a distant cousin, Raymond Raskin. They had two children, Jonathan, born 1951 and Lisa, born 1953. She made her professional debut on both the stage and on television during the 1950s at the same time that she was raising her family. Even after undergoing a radical mastectomy in 1962, Raskin continued her operatic career, specializing in Schubert, Mozart, lieder and Yiddish songs on both the stage and in numerous recordings with major labels. During the 1970s she turned to teaching while still performing. In 1982 Raskin was diagnosed with ovarian cancer and died December 21, 1984.
For more detailed biographical information, see the entry on Raskin in Current Biography (April 1964) and the entry by Paula Eisenstein Baker in Jewish Women in American: An Historical Encyclopedia (1997). There is also a small folder of materials on Raskin in the Smith College Archives, in 80.Cla 1949 and in 12.HD.
The bulk of the papers date from the early 1960s through the early 1980s and focus on Raskin's professional life, including publicity, reviews and programs. There are also a number of recordings of Raskin's performances from the 1950s to the 1970s. There is a small amount of personal material, including diaries and correspondence, primarily from her high school and college years. There is also some personal correspondence with family and friends. Notable correspondents include Beverly Sills, Eugene Ormandy, and William Maxwell.
This collection is organized into five series:
I. Biographical
II. Correspondence
III. Professional Activities
IV. Photographs and Scrapbooks
V. Audiotapes
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The collection is open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The papers were donated to the Sophia Smith Collection by Judith Raskin in 1977. Since her death, additions to the collection have been made by her daughter Lisa Raskin as well as by Adrienne Auerswald and Mary Elizabeth Ford.
Search Terms
Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.)--History--Sources; Opera--United States--History-20th century--Sources; Singers--United States--History-20th century--Sources; Smith College--Students--History--Sources; Raskin, Judith; Hamlin, Anna M.; Maxwell, William, 1908- --Correspondence; Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985--Correspondence; Sills, Beverly--Correspondence
Additional Information
Related Material
For more detailed biographical information, see the entry on Raskin in Current Biography (April 1964) and the entry by Paula Eisenstein Baker in Jewish Women in American: An Historical Encyclopedia (1997). There is also a small folder of materials on Raskin in the Smith College Archives, in 80.Cla 1949 and in 12.HD.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL 1937-1995, .75 linear ft.
  This series includes diaries, school records, calendars, and tributes to Judith Raskin, both in life and death. Of particular note is a piece written by Raskin's mother, Lillian Mendelsohn Raskin, in 1949, entitled A Parent Inquires: How can I help my gifted child? Raskin's death and funeral are covered with various eulogies, obituaries, and information on the memorial recitals performed in her name.
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE 1911-1986, 1 linear ft.
  This series includes correspondence with both family members and friends and associates. A major portion of the family correspondence is from Judith Raskin to her parents during her first three years at Smith. There is also a significant amount of correspondence between Raskin and fellow Smith alumna Mary Elizabeth Ford during the 1960s. In addition to fan mail there is a sizable number of condolences received by the Raskin family after Judith Raskin's death in 1984. The correspondence between Raskin and Anna Hamlin is of particular interest in that operatic technique is freely discussed by both student and teacher.
- SERIES III. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES 1947-1984, 2.7 linear ft.
  This series comprises the bulk of the collection and includes programs from Raskin's performances over the years as well as reviews, articles, and press materials both by and about Raskin. Also included in this series are financial records, contracts, and notes regarding repertoire and technique by both Anna Hamlin and Raskin. Of special interest is the collection of correspondence and site reports from Raskin's participation in the National Endowment for the Arts.
- SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS AND SCRAPBOOKS 1917-1973, 1.85 linear ft.
  This series includes publicity head shots and portraits, an extensive collection of photos of Raskin in performance and rehearsal, and some personal photographs of Raskin and others. Quite notable is the exhaustive collection of photographs detailing the rehearsal and staging of the NBC Opera's Don Giovanni, starring Raskin, Cesare Siepi, and Leontyne Price. Other photos of note are the framed and autographed photographs of Raskin's teacher Anna Hamlin, taken in 1926 and the 1917 shot of Hamlin's teacher, Marcella Sembrich.
- SERIES V. AUDIOTAPES 1959-1978, undated, 3 linear ft.
  This series consists of 47 reel-to-reel tapes and 9 cassette tapes, containing mostly rehearsal sessions and actual performances. There is also some family material as well as interviews with Raskin. See also records and tapes held by the Werner Josten Library, Smith College.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL 1937-1995
  - Diaries, 1939, 1942-43 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Inserts removed from diaries, 1939, 1942-43 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Calendars, 1967-71, 1975-76 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Schoolwork (4th grade), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - High School
    - Report cards, 1941-44 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Yearbook, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "A Parent Inquires: How can I help my gifted child?," Lillian Raskin, undated, circa 1949 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Smith College
    - Honorary Degree, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "Dear Baldwin 49'ers," letter to Baldwin housemates, 1964. (Box 1, Folder 10a)
    - Typescript, Judith Raskin interview, College: A Smith Mosaic 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Curriculum vitae, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Memorial tributes, 1986, 1995 (Box 1a, Folder 1)
  - Death and memorial service: obituaries, elegies, eulogies, etc., 1984 (Box 1a, Folder 2)
  - Memorial recitals: correspondence, announcements and programs, reviews and press materials, 1985-1999 (Box 1a, Folder 3)
  - Memorial Scholarships, 1980s (Box 1a, Folder 4)
  - Family memorabilia, 1920s-80s (Box 1a, Folder 5)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE 1911-1986
  - Family
    - Judith Raskin
      - Lillian and Harry Raskin (parents), 1945-48 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
      - Lillian Raskin, 1963-70 (Box 2, Folder 4-7)
      - Lillian Raskin, undated (circa 1960s) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Re: Death of Harry Raskin, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Jon and Lisa Raskin (children), 1962-74, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Re: Kingsley Hall School, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Other relatives, 1940-47 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Lillian and Harry Raskin
      - From Ray Raskin, undated, circa 1940s (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - From others, 1911, 1944-49, 1964, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Friends and associates
    - Mary Elizabeth Ford, 1961-88 (Box 2, Folder 15-18)
    - Anna Hamlin, 1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Jo Hamlin, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - William Maxwell, 1973, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Adrienne Auerswald, 1964-65 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - General, 1946-84, undated (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
  - Professional, 1954-84, undated (Box 3, Folder 5-8)
  - Professional, Sir Rudolf Bing, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8a)
  - Fan mail
    - 1963-78, undated (Box 3, Folder 9-10)
    - P.S. 175, April 1962 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Condolences
    - A-M (Box 3, Folder 12-18)
    - N-Z (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
- SERIES III. PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES 1947-1984
  - Opera performance/teaching
    - Repertoire, technique, and translations (Box 4, Folder 5-7)
    - Notes re: singing from Anna Hamlin (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Singing evaluations, 1950, 1954, undated (circa 1957) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Contracts and certificates, 1964-1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Financial records, 1946, 1949, 1963, 1964, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Contracts and financial records, 1972-73 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Contracts and financial records, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Contracts and financial records, 1977, 1978, 1980, 1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Master classes, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Ludwig Lustig, 1966-69 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Concert programs
      - 1947-69 (Box 5, Folder 1-11)
      - 1969-79 (Box 6, Folder 1-9)
      - 1979-1984, undated (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
    - Television appearance, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Articles about Judith Raskin, 1960-2000, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Performance announcements, 1957-81, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Performance reviews, 1955-82, undated (Box 8, Folder 3-6)
    - Articles and unpublished pieces by Judith Raskin, 1964-69, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Recordings
    - Reviews, 1964-1980, undated (Box 8a, Folder 1)
    - Announcements, 1964-1967, undated (Box 8a, Folder 2)
  - Opera Performance/teaching
    - Press materials, 1950-1982, undated (Box 8a, Folder 3)
    - Performances by others, 1950-82, undated (Box 8a, Folder 4)
  - Other activities
    - Miscellaneous boards, 1973-77 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 92nd Street Y, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, 1974-1976
    - Correspondence, 1974-1976, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Site reports and evaluations, 1974-1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Notes, undated, articles, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS AND SCRAPBOOKS 1917-1973
  - Photographs
    - Personal, 1930s-1980s, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Publicity head shots and portraits, 1950s-1980s, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Deseret," NBC Opera. (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Performance and rehearsals, 1950s-1980s, undated (Box 9a, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous/unidentified, 1964, 1967, undated (Box 9a, Folder 3)
    - Mary Elizabeth Ford, fall 1966 (Box 9a, Folder 4)
    - Marcella Sembrich, 1917 (Box 9b, Folder 1)
    - Anna Hamlin, 1926 (Box 9b, Folder 2)
    - "Don Giovanni" rehearsals and performance, NBC Opera, April 1961 (Box 9c)
    - Oversize photos and posters, 1960, 1973, undated (Box 10)
    - Scrapbooks, 1947-1973 (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
- SERIES V. AUDIOTAPES 1959-1978, undated
  - Reel-to-Reel
    - Side 1: 26 April 1959: Song of Solomon, Ezra Laderman, conductor, (Raskin), CBS-TV (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Side 2: n.d.: R. Strauss--"Four Last Songs," Lisa Della Casa, soprano, Karl Böhm, conductor, Salzburg Festival (Box 12)
    - Side 1: 3 Nov 1959: Beethoven, Fidelio excerpts, NBC-TV (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Side 2: 28 Sept 1961: Beethoven, Symphony No. 9 (Last Movement), Eugene Ormandy and the Philadelphia Orchestra (Raskin, Rosalind Elias, Richard Tucker, Jerome Hines), UN Memorial to Dag Hammarskjöld; and Donizetti, "Regnava nel silenzio" (Lucia di Lammermoor); Schubert, "Mein Herz ist schwer" ("Gretchen am Spinnrade"); and Verdi, (Recitative) "È strano!" and (Aria) "Sempre libera" (La Traviata) at Anna Hamlin's, n.d. (Box 12)
    - Side 1: 6 Dec 1959: Mozart--"Ach, ich liebte" (Die Entführung aus dem serail); 11 Dec 1959: "Lisa's Birthday Party"; 4 Jan 1960: Donizetti--Lucia di Lammermoor; 1960: "Jon's party" (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Side 2: 1960: "Jon plays Bach"; Dec 1960:"Lisa's party"; 1961: "Jon's party"; 4 Jan 1960: Willow Song (Box 12)
    - Side 1: 6 Mar 1960: Little Orchestra Society (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Side 2: Little Orchestra Society, (cont'd); n.d., Harry Raskin, piano, Haydn--"Andante con Variazioni" (Box 12)
    - Side 1: 10 April 1960: Mozart--(Scenes from Don Giovanni) "Giovinette, che fate all amore," "Là ci darem la mano," "Batti, batti"; 8 Dec 1957: Poulenc--(The Carmelites) Sister Constance (III, V, VI, Last) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Side 2: Oct 1961: Mozart--Così Fan Tutte, City Center, NYC; 20 April 1962: Bach--(St. John Passion) "Ich folge dir gleichfalls mit freudigen schritten"; and Beethoven--Symphony No. 9 (Movement IV), Eugene Ormandy, conductor (Raskin, Rosalind Elias, Richard Tucker, Jerome Hines), Carnegie Hall (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Side 1: 6 Feb 1962: Handel--(Samson excerpts): "Ye Men of Gaza" (Raskin), "With Plaintive Notes" (Raskin), "Your Charms to Ruin Led the Way" (Jon Vickers), "My Faith and Truth" (Raskin), "Traitor to Love" (Raskin and Vickers), "Honor and Arms" (Norman Treigle) and "Go, Coward, Go" (Vickers and Treigle), American Orchestra (Raskin, Norman Treigle, Jon Vickers, Claire Watson, Russell Oberlin), Carnegie Hall (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Side 2: 22 Dec 1961: Bach--(Christmas Oratorio): "Herr, dein Mitleid" (Raskin and Ara Berberian), "Immanuel, o süsses Wort" (Raskin and Berberian), "Ach! Wann wird die Zeit erscheinen" (Raskin, Joan Caplan, and Charles Bressler), Recitative "Du Falscher" and Aria "Nur ein Wink" (Raskin); and Bellini (La Sonnambula)--"Ah! non giunge" (Joan Sutherland), Thomas Dunn, conductor, Carnegie Hall (Box 12)
    - Side 1: 1962: Scarlatti, Sonata; Bach,--Prelude and Fugue; and Bach--Italian Concerto, Harry Raskin, piano (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Side 1: 23 Feb 1962: Mozart--Le Nozze di Figaro excerpts, Ignace Strasfogel, conductor (Raskin [debut], Lisa Della Casa, Mildred Miller, Giorgio Tozzi, Walter Cassel) Metropolitan Opera, NYC (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Side 2: end of Figaro; 4 Feb 1962: Rossini--Count Ory excerpts, Thomas Schippers, conductor (Raskin, Shirley Verrett-Carter, Helen Vanni, Frank Poretta, Norman Treigle), NY Philharmonic broadcast; 19 Oct 1958: Mozart (Concert Aria)--"Mia speranza adorata!", Margareta Hallin Guilini, conductor, Swedish Radio Orchestra (Box 12)
    - Side 1: n.d., circa 1962: Verdi--Falstaff, Act 1 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Side 2: n.d., circa 1962: Verdi--Falstaff, Act 2 (Box 12)
    - Side 1: n.d., circa 1962: Falstaff, Act 3, Scenes 1 and 2; 24 Sept 1962: Barber--Piano Concerto, John Browning, pianist, live broadcast (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Side 1 (broadcast 6 Oct 1962): Schubert--"Die Forelle," "Geheimes," "Gretchen am Spinnrade," and "Seligkeit"; R. Strauss--"Ich schwebe," and "Schlagende Herzen"; Debussy--"Fantoches," "Receuillement"; Poulenc--"Air Champêtre," "Air Grave," and "Air Vif"; Barber--"Knoxville: Summer of 1915", Anne Macfarlane, accompanist, Recital Hall, NBC-TV, 2 Oct 1962 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Side 1: 5 Jan 1963: Handel--Psalm 112, Frederic Waldman, conductor, Metropolitan Museum (broadcast live WNYC); n.d.: Handel--Messiah excerpts ("Rejoice Greatly," "I Know That My Redeemer Liveth"), Eugene Ormandy, conductor (recorded in Philadelphia, broadcast on WQXR) (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Side 2: 5 Jan 1963: Haydn--Mass in B-Flat ("Theresien"), Frederic Waldman, conductor (Raskin, Joanna Simon, Charles Bressler, Chester Watson), Metropolitan Museum (broadcast live WNYC) (Box 12)
    - Side 1: 15 Mar 1963: Mozart--Exsultate Jubilate, "Aer tranquillo (Il Re Pastore), "Ruhe sanft, mein holdes leben (Zaide), "Bella Mia Fiamma" (Concert Aria), (Raskin, Thomas Dunn) Metropolitan Museum (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Side 2: 26 Jan 1963: Beethoven--Fidelio, Karl Boehm, conductor, Act I, Scene 1 (Raskin, Birgit Nilsson, Charles Anthony, Ernst Wiemann, Morley Meredith, Jon Vickers) Met Broadcast (Box 12)
    - Summer 1963: Mozart--Die Zauberflöte, Act I, Glyndebourne Festival, England (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Summer 1963: Mozart--Die Zauberflöte, Act II, Glyndebourne Festival, England (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Side 1: 24 Sept 1963: R. Strauss--Die Rosenkavalier excerpts, Leonard Bernstein, conductor (Raskin, Regina Sarfaty), New York Philharmonic, Philharmonic Hall; 14 Mar 1964: Donizetti--Anna Bolena excerpt, Met Intermission (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Side 2: April 1963: Bach (St. Matthew Passion)--"Bleed and Break," "Lord, to Thee," "Aus Liebe" ("In love my Saviour now is dying"), and (Duet) "Behold, my Saviour" (Raskin, Maureen Forrester), NBC-TV (Box 12)
    - Side 1: 2 Oct 1963: Ezra Laderman-Archibald MacLeish--Songs of Eve (Raskin, T. Mayer), University of New Hampshire (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Side 2: 24 Nov 1963: Bach--Jauchzet Gott (Cantata No. 51) (Raskin, T. Dunn), Philharmonic Hall (Box 12)
    - Side 1: 16 Oct 1963: Puccini--La Bohème excerpts, Act III (concl.) and Act IV (Raskin, Ryan, Patricia Brooks, Craig, Bertolind, Thomas Paul, Metcalf) NYC Opera, Middletown, NY; 11 Feb 1963: Mahler--Symphony No. 4, 4th Movement, George Szell, conductor; 14 Jan 1964: Rossini (Barber of Seville)--"Una Voce Poco Fa," (Duet) "Dunque Io Son" (Raskin, William Walker) Bell Telephone Hour, NBC-TV; 24 Sept 1963: R. Strauss--Die Rosenkavalier, Act II-Presentation of the Rose, Leonard Bernstein, conductor (Raskin, Regina Sarfaty), New York Philharmonic Orchestra, Philharmonic Hall (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Side 2: 16 Oct 1963: Puccini--La Bohème excerpts, Acts I and III [beginning with Mimi's entrance, ending after the coat song] (Raskin, Ryan, Patricia Brooks, Craig, Bertolind, Thomas Paul, Metcalf) NYC Opera, Middletown, NY (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - 14 Jan 1964: Rossini--The Barber of Seville, Bell Telephone Hour, NBC-TV (Box 12, Folder 19)
      [See above]
    - 14 Jan 1964: Rossini--The Barber of Seville (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - 14 Mar 1964: "Opera News on the Air," Puccini--La Bohème; Sept. 1965: Mahler--Symphony No. 4 (Last Movement), Cleveland broadcast; n.d.: Donizetti--Anna Bolena selection (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Summer 1964: Mozart--Die Zauberflöte (Raskin-"Pamina", Ragnar Ulfong-"Tamino", Heinz Blanken-burg-"Papageno") Bryon Balkwill, conductor, Glyndebourne Festival, England (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Summer 1964: Mozart--Die Zauberflöte (Raskin-"Pamina", Ragnar Ulfong-"Tamino", Heinz Blanken-burg-"Papageno") Bryon Balkwill, conductor, Glyndebourne Festival, England Geheimes," "Gretchen am Spinnrade," "Der Jüngling an der Quelle," "Auflösung," "Seligkeit"; Mahler--"Liebst du um Schönheit," "Ablösung im Sommer," "Ich atmet' einen linden Duft," and "Wer hat dies Liedlein erdacht?", Ford Foundation recital, Rogers Auditorium, Metropolitan Museum (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - 1964: Rossini--Il Turco in Italia (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Side 1: 2 Jan 1965: Mozart--Le Nozze di Figaro, Joseph Rosenstock, conductor (Raskin, Lisa Della Casa, Teresa Stratas, Kriese, Blair, Giorgio Tozzi, Herman Prey, Esparza), Act I (Bartolo's Aria omitted), Met broadcast (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Side 2: Figaro, Act II (Box 12)
    - Side 1: 7 Mar 1965: Haydn--The Creation, Parts I and II, Musica Aeterna, Grace R. Rogers Auditorium, Metropolitan Museum (broadcast WNYC) (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Side 2: The Creation, Part III (Box 12)
    - 16 Mar 1965: Smith College Recital, 1st half, John M. Greene Hall (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - 16 Mar 1965: Smith College Recital, 2nd half, John M. Greene Hall (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Side 1: 5 Dec 1965: "Through Intermission," Town Hall, New York (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Side 2: 5 Dec 1965: "After Intermission," Town Hall, New York (Box 12)
    - 5 Dec 1965: Part I: Beethoven--"Die Trommel gerühret," "Freudvoll und leidvoll," and "Neue Liebe, neues Leben"; and Schubert--"Geheimnis," "Auflösing," "Der Jüngling an der Quelle," "Suleika," "Neue Liebe," "Die Liebende Scheibt," "Italien [Fanny Mendelssohn]," and "Frühlingsleid," George Schick, piano, Town Hall, New York (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - 5 Dec 1965: Part II: see above (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - 19 Feb 1966: Donizetti--Lucia di Lammermoor, "Singers Round Table," M.C. Edward Downes with Licia Albanese, Judith Raskin, Cesare Siepi, and Geraint Evans, Opera News on the Air (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Side 1: May 1966: Mozart--"L'Amerò" (Il Re Pastore), "Batti, batti" (Don Giovanni), and "Welche Wonne" (Seraglio); Lehar--"Vilia" (The Merry Widow); and Johann Strauss--"Tales From The Vienna Woods," and "Laughing Song" (Die Fledermaus), Cleveland Orchestra Concert, Louis Lane, conductor; n.d.: part of Don Giovanni (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Side 2: 29 Jan 1966: Mozart--Don Giovanni, Act II, Joseph Rosenstock, conductor (Teresa Stich-Randall, Elisabeth Schwarzkopf, Rosalind Elias, Cesare Siepi, Geraint Evans, Jan Peerce, and Theodore Uppmann), Metropolitan Opera (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Side 1: Aug 1966: Mozart--The Magic Flute (excerpts), Tanglewood, Erich Leinsdorf, conductor (Raskin, George Shirley, John Reardon, Nico Castel, Ezio Flagello, Jane Marsh, Veronica Tyler, Joanna Simon, Batyah Godfrey, Beverly Sills) (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Side 2: n.d.: Mahler--Symphony No. 4 (Last Movement), George Szell, conductor, Live from Cleveland (Box 12)
    - 4 Dec 1966: Town Hall Recital, George Schick, piano (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - 4 Dec 1966: Master reels for privately produced LP: "Judith Raskin, Volume III, Town Hall Recital," George Schick, piano, (performing Mozart, Schubert, Brahms, Wolf, Strauss); corr.: Ray Raskin to Paul, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 36-38)
    - 4 Mar 1967: Mozart--The Magic Flute, Josef Krips, conductor, (Raskin as Pamina, George Shirley, Theodor Uppman, Roberta Peters, Walter Cassel), Metropolitan Opera Broadcast (WQXR- FM) (Box 13, Folder 39-42)
    - 6 Nov 1967: Haydn--"Sinfonia Concertante, Op. 84"; Berlioz--"Les Nuits d'été, Op. 7," Pierre Boulez, conductor, Severance Hall Concert (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - 24 Feb 1968: Performing works by Franz, Schubert, Mendelssohn, Wolf, and Strauss, George Schick, piano, Met Museum (Box 13, Folder 44-45)
    - Jun 1969: R. Strauss--Die Rosenkavalier (excerpts), Metropolitan Opera (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - 7 Oct 1970: Selections from Mozart, Schubert, Brahms, Berg, and Mahler, George Schick, piano, NY Cultural Center (program enclosed) (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - 29 Mar 1971: Handel--Ariodante, Carnegie Hall (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - 3 Mar 1974: Medieval/Renaissance Recital, Cloisters and (Box 13, Folder 49-50)
    - 11 May 1975: Mozart--"An Chloe," and "Als Luise," "Warnung"; Schubert--"An Die Musik," "Im Frühling," "Frühlingstraum," and "Seligkeit"; Martin Isepp, piano, Master's School Theatre, Dobbs Ferry, NY (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - 11 May 1975: Schumann--"Frauenliebe und Leben", Martin Isepp, piano, Master's School Theatre, Dobbs Ferry, NY (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - 11 May 1975: Barber--"The Monk and His Cat," and "Saint Ita's Vision"; Rorem--"I am Rose," and "Youth, Day, Old Age, and Night"; Laderman--"Eve in the Dawn," "The Riddles", Martin Isepp, piano, Master's School Theatre, Dobbs Ferry, NY (Box 13, Folder 53)